William S. Theaker Papers VHP2004/18
CCSU Veterans History Project
William S. Theaker Papers
Bulk, 1964-1967
1964-1967, 2004
VHP2004/18
CCSU Veterans History Project
65.0 Digital objects 1 interview DVD
Theaker, William S., (William Samuel), 1944 -
Biographical/Historical note
William S. Theaker enlisted in the U.S. Army in May of 1964 after finishing two years of college. He enlisted before any sign of war in Vietnam appeared. He attended basic training at Fort Dix (NJ). From there he went to Fort Sill (OK) for artillery training, and Fort Benning (GA) for jump school. It was during jump school that Theaker was chosen for Special Forces. He was then sent to Fort Bragg (NC), where he was trained as a medic. The situation in Vietnam had begun to escalate and in February of 1966, Theaker was sent to Vietnam where he was assigned to a reconnaissance unit as a medic. During his special forces training, Theaker also trained as a lab technician, and after 5 months of working in the field as a medic, he was transferred to a lab to work as a tech. He was sent home in early 1967, where he worked as a lab tech for a time before returning to college at Temple University.
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for Research
Custodial History note
All manuscripts and photographs donated were digitized and digitally preserved. The donor retained all original manuscripts and photographs.
Online Access
An online exhibition of this veteran's papers can be accessed at project's website
United States. Army. Infantry Regiment, 26th .; United States. Army.; Di~ An (Vietnam: District); Fort Dix (N.J.); Fort Sam Houston (Tex.); Parris Island (S.C.); United States. Army. Special Forces; Vietnam War, 1961-1975; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Personal narrative, American
- Series I: Personal Papers
  - Azimuths and Angels: a military memoir, VHP2004/18.I.1; 9.0 Digital objects
  - Jumping for Joy, a military memoir, n.d.; VHP2004/18.I.2; 5.0 Digital objects
  - Looped, a military memoir, n.d.; VHP2004/18.I.3; 2.0 Digital objects
  - Flower Children, a military memoir, n.d.; VHP2004/18.I.4; 2.0 Digital objects
  - Sunshine, Lab Luck & A Little Bit of Soap, a military memoir, n.d.; VHP2004/18.I.5; 5.0 Digital objects
  - Here Be Monsters, a military memoir, n.d.; VHP2004/18.I.6; 5.0 Digital objects
  - Up, Please, a military memoir, n.d.; VHP2004/18.I.7; 10.0 Digital objects
  - Up Against the Wall, a military memoir, n.d.; VHP2004/18.I.8; 3.0 Digital objects
  - Pour Me, a military memoir, n.d.; VHP2004/18.I.9; 8.0 Digital objects
  - The Color Purple, a military memoir, n.d.; VHP2004/18.I.10; 3.0 Digital objects
  - You Be the Judge, a military memoir, n.d.; VHP2004/18.I.11; 2.0 Digital objects
  - Close Friends, a military memoir, VHP2004/18.I.12; 5.0 Digital objects
  - Homeward Bound, a military memoir, VHP2004/18.I.13; 2.0 Digital objects
  - Interview Synopsis, February 16, 2004; VHP2004/18.I.14
- Series II: Multi-Media
  - Subseries A: Still Images
    - William “Sam” Theaker in lab where he worked as a lab technician - Vietnam, 1966; VHP2004/18.II.1
  - Subseries B: Moving Images
    - Oral History Interview, February 16, 2004; VHP2004/18.II.b.1; 1.0 dvd (Disk DVD VHP2004/18, Box VHP Interview 1)
      Existence and Location of Copies note
      Interview video also available online.
      Streaming Video